(杰森和麦琪晚上正在看恐怖电影.有人在屋外爬上了一架梯子.)
(Jason and Maggie are watching a sad film at night.Someone climbs up a ladder outside the house.)
麦琪:你听到声音了么?
Maggie: Did you hear that?
杰森:刺拉的声音?
Jason: What that kind of scraping sound?
麦琪:对.
Maggie: Yeah.
杰森:动静,房顶上的?
Jason: Was it up on the roof?
麦琪:对.
Maggie: Yeah.
杰森: 不,我没听到,没听到有动静.
Jason: No, I didn't.I didn't hear that one either.
麦琪:杰森!
Maggie: Jason!
杰森:好吧,我会去瞧瞧的,等……
Jason: Ok, I'll handle it, wait...
麦琪:哦,天哪!
Maggie: Ooh gosh!
杰森:你准备让我一个对付?
Jason: Are you gonna let me handle this myself?
(迈克爬过窗户)
(Mike crawls through the window)
迈克:好!!
Mike: Alright!!
(麦琪和杰森冲出房间,大声呵斥,迈克尖叫)
(Maggie and Jason jump out of a room shouting and Mike screams)
迈克:是我,我在回家的路上,
Mike: Errm, I was on my way home,
我觉得我时间充裕---离午夜还早---你也知道,我会守规矩按时睡觉的.
and I figured I had plenty of time to get home before midnight because
所以,我觉得我还是挺听话的,
as you know, I wouldn't miss my curfew.
我看到一个东西,你们觉得会是什么?
So there I was feeling pretty obedient, when what do you think I saw?
杰森:宇宙飞船?!
Jason: A spaceship?!
迈克:好了,爸爸,别揶揄我了!
Mike: Come on Dad, don't be ridiculous!I saw...fire.
我看到了……火.对,我看到了冲天大火.
Yeah, I saw a towering fire.
麦琪:哦,我的……!
Maggie: Oh my!
迈克:而后,我对自己说,"
Mike: So then I said to myself, "Mike, you got two choices.
迈克,你有两个选择.
Either you can turn your head the other way and make your curfew,
或者你袖手旁观,按时回家睡觉,或者晚回家会儿,
or you can be a measly two hours and ten minutes late,
也就两小时零十分钟的样子,可以挽救几个人的生命."
and save a few lives.
麦琪:哇.
Maggie: Wow.
杰森:多好的孩子啊.
Jason: What a kid.
迈克:所以,顾不上我个人的安危,也顾不上按时回家睡觉的时间……
Mike: So with no concern for my personal safety, or the time...
杰森:现在才00:11:30了.
Jason: It's eleven thirty.
迈克:我知道.所以,顾不上……什么?
Mike: I know.So with no concern for...what?
麦琪:现在才00:11:30了现在,迈克.
Maggie: It's eleven thirty right now Mike.
离你的睡觉时间还有整整半小时.
A whole half hour before your curfew.
迈克:鲍纳!
Mike: Boner!
杰森:你可以继续说完.
Jason: You might say that.
迈克:不不不不.鲍纳一定是看错时间了.嘿!这是给我们大家伙儿开的一个玩笑.我12点之前回来.
Mike: No no no no.Boner must have got the time wrong.Ha!I guess the jokes on all of us.I'll be back before twelve.
麦琪:哦,不.
Maggie: Oh no.
迈克:好了好了,根本没有什么冲天大火.
Mike: Ok ok, so there was no towering inferno.
麦琪和杰森:没有??
Maggie and Jason: No??
麦琪:那就是说你承认你刚才是在欺骗我们了?
Maggie: So you admit that you lied to us?
迈克:"欺骗"这词儿太难听了.
Mike: "Lie" is such an ugly word.
杰森:你好,麦琪!
Jason: Hello Maggie!!Suitcases are in the car.
手提箱在车上.等你父母到的时候我们再走也不迟.
We can go just as soon as your parents get here.
好了,宝贝,
Oh come on honey, cheer up!
高兴点!再过两小时,
In two hours you'll be cavorting in Atlantic City with a group of five
你们就会在亚特兰大市欢呼雀跃了,一块儿的有五千多开会的精神病科大夫.
thousand conventioning psychiatrists.Come on,
如果你真想休息一下,那就这个周末吧.
if you're ever gonna have a breakdown, this is the weekend to do it.
麦琪:杰森,问题的关键不是迈克撒了谎,而是他一贯撒谎.
Maggie: Jason, it's not that Mike lies, it's that he does it so often.
杰森:不管怎么说,他撒谎撒得还不是很好,还骗不住你.
Jason: Well, at least he doesn't do it well.
麦琪:我是认真的.
Maggie: I'm serious.
杰森:好了,麦琪,
Jason: Oh come on Maggie, he's sixteen.
他才16岁.你肯定,
I'm sure when you were sixteen,
你16的时候,你也会对你们家里人撒谎的.
you must have lied to your folks once in a while.
麦琪:我没撒!我决不会跟迈克那样,决不会!
Maggie: I did not!I was never like Mike, never!
本:爷爷还没到么?
Ben: Is Grandpa here yet?
杰森:他随时都会到.
Jason: He'll be here any minute.
本:他来的时候,我要藏起来吓他一吓.
Ben: I'm gonna ambush Grandpa when he comes.
杰森:好了,先吃你饭.
Jason: Well eat your breakfast first.
本:哦!
Ben: Oh!
麦琪:咱们把他关起来!
Maggie: Let's ground him!
本:我吃,我吃.
Ben: I'll eat, I'll eat.
杰森:我们说的是迈克.
Jason: We're talking about Mike.
本:把他关起来.
Ben: Ground him.
杰森:但是,我们能这么做么?
Jason: But we can't,
我们这周末得去参加精神病科医生的一个会议.
we're gonna be away at a psychiatric conference this weekend.
麦琪:但我父母会来这儿,而且我爸爸他从警察局退下来有三年多了.
Maggie: But my parents will be here,
我觉得,
and my Dad's been retired from the police force for over three years now.
让他重操旧业把迈克锁起来,简直太妙了.
I mean it would be really sweet to let him lock somebody up again.
迈克:早上好,妈妈!早上好,爸爸!
Mike: Good morning Mother!Morning Dad!Morning little Ben!
早上好,本!我想你们都在琢磨,为什么我穿这身绉巴巴,烂希希的衬衫.
I guess you're all wondering why
I'm standing here wearing this wrinkled, tattered shirt
麦琪:不.
Maggie: No.
麦琪:那……就让我解释一下.我昨晚上,
Mike: Well...just let me explain.
一宿没睡,
Ok now, I was up all last night with worry; thinking about...
担心啊;我在想……我都做了些什么,都错在什么地方.
what I did and why it was so wrong.
以及,
And what I can do to make it up to you,
我可以做些什么向您二位来将功补过,您二位是我生命中最最重要的人.
the two most important people in my life.
麦琪:好了,我们也一直在考虑关于迈克的事.
Maggie: Well we've been doing some thinking too Mike.
迈克:哦!好,那……那就让我跟您解释一下我的想法.
Mike: Oh!Well j...just let me run my thoughts by you.
麦琪:迈克,我真的……
Maggie: Mike, I really...
杰森:等等,麦琪.这样也许很好.
Jason: Wait wait Maggie, this might be good.
麦琪:本,你赶紧吃你的早饭,准备去接你爷爷.
Maggie: Ben, maybe you better take your breakfast and get ready to go jump Grandpa
本:我就想看到迈克受刑!
Ben: I wanna watch Mike suffer!
杰森:本,你妈妈不是告诉你了么,走,去埋伏埋伏吓你爷爷去.
Jason: Ben, your mother told you to please go ambush your grandfather.
迈克:好!首先,昨晚我准时回来睡觉了.其次,
Mike: Ok!Alright now one, I was actually on time.
我承认自己撒谎了,很坦率而且很诚实.第三,……
And two, I admitted openly and honestly that I lied.And three...
杰森:还有第三?你关在这屋子里,
Maggie: And three, you are grounded to this house for the remainder of
从现在到这周末,哪儿都不许去;八点上床,不许看电视.
the weekend, in bed by eight, and no TV.
杰森:换个角度这么想,迈克,三分你已经赢了两分.
Jason: Well look at it this way Mike, you won two out of three points.
开萝尔:妈妈,爷爷奶奶在这儿的时候,我去沃恩德家,可以么?
Carol: Mom, is it ok if I stay over at Wanda's while Grandma and Grandpa
are here
麦琪:开萝尔,
Maggie: Carol, is it really going to hurt you to spend one whole weekend
呆在家里跟你的爷爷奶奶一起过个周末真的会让你觉得很难受很受伤害么?
here with your grandparents?
开萝尔:身体方面的伤害倒没有,但……
Carol: Well not physically, but...
麦琪:给你的回答,不行.
Maggie: The answer is no.
迈克:妈妈,你不可以这周末把我关起来.
Mike: Mom, you can't ground me this weekend.
麦琪:不,我可以.得让你长长记性,撒谎不对.
Maggie: Oh yes I can.You have to learn that lying is wrong.
迈克:妈妈!我这周末已经有重要的安排了.
Mike: Mom!I have got major plans this weekend.
麦琪:想打赌么?
Maggie: Wanna bet?
(电话响起)
(phone rings)
麦琪:你好.哦,苏珊,
Maggie: Hello.Oh Susan, what's up?
什么事?哦,克利斯托弗会在这周末报道这条新闻的.
Oh, I thought Christopher was gonna cover that story this weekend.Today?
今天?我做不了.我知道你可以说成是命令逼我接受,
Well I can't do it.
但是我要去亚特兰大市……这不是借口.呃……这样的,
I know you can make it an order, but see I'm going to Atlantic City with...
我要去参加我阿姨玛丽亚的婚礼,我是……我是婚礼嘉宾团成员.我也感到很遗憾,
it's not a flimsy excuse.Erm...
苏珊.除了这周末,其它周末,
See I'm going to my Aunt Marjie's wedding, I'm...I'm in the wedding.
我都会有空.你也一样.再见.
I'm sorry too Susan.Any other weekend I'd be available.Right you too.Bye bye.
迈克:"谎言是:欺骗,子虚乌有,虚假,错误."
Mike: "Lie: A deception, a fabrication, an untruth, a falsehood."
杰森:好了,我们确实进退维谷,
Jason: Well, I admit we do have something of a dilemma honey,
亲爱的,但是可以妥善的解决话这也不是什么大问题.事实上,
but it's not a problem that can't be solved.
解决方案非常简单,就是把你也给关起来.
In fact the solution is really very simple, you're grounded too.
麦琪:开什么玩笑!
Maggie: Very funny!
杰森:真的.
Jason: Yes.
麦琪:可是,说正经的,亲爱的,我们……你当真呢!
Maggie: But seriously honey we...you are serious!
杰森:啊!
Jason: Well!
麦琪:哦,杰森,那太离谱了.
Maggie: Oh Jason that's absurd.
杰森:你说的没错.
Jason: You're right.
麦琪:我觉得,那么做也于事无补.
Maggie: I don't see how it would help anything.
我觉得,我们也不是在严肃地讨论这事儿.
I don't believe we are even discussing it.
杰森:你说的没错.
Jason: You are right.
麦琪:讨厌你这样子,
Maggie: I hate it when you say "you're right" when you really mean "you're
嘴上说的是"你说的没错"心里说的却是"你错了"
wrong".
杰森:不要放在心上,把你关起来的话就当我没说.
Jason: Forget I even mentioned you being grounded.
也不要放在心上,要告诫迈克---说谎对任何人来说都是错误的.
Forget that it would teach Mike that lying is wrong for everyone.
也不要放在心上,……
Forget that...
麦琪:杰森!我讨厌你这样子,最讨厌你这个.
Maggie: Jason!I hate this, more than I hate the other thing.
杰森:你说的没错.
Jason: You're right.
麦琪:你又来了.
Maggie: You're doing it again.
杰森:对不起.我去告诉迈克,只要你不是根据欧文*艾伦的灾难片扯的谎,说谎并没什么大不了的.
Jason: I'm sorry.I will go and tell Mike that it's alright to lie,
(注:迈克刚才撒谎找的借口是冲天的大火.很可能是看完灾难片后得到的启发.)
as long as you don't base it on an Irwin Allen disaster movie.
麦琪:杰森.
Maggie: Jason.
杰森:怎么?
Jason: Yes.
麦琪:我不想被关禁闭.
Maggie: I don't want to be grounded.
杰森:亲爱的,亲爱的,只不过两天的专题讨论,什么精神分裂了,
Jason: Honey, it's only two days of workshops on schizophrenia, paranoia,
偏执狂了,恐惧症了,恋物癖了.
phobias, fetishism.
麦琪:听起来蛮有趣的哦.
Maggie: Sounds fun.
杰森:想像一下,当我们识破迈克借口火灾想逃脱惩罚时,
Jason: Well just imagine the look on Mike's face when we tell him that
他脸上的那副表情.
his sure fire escape from punishment doesn't work.
迈克:你应该先看看妈妈脸上的那副表情,她撒了谎让我逮住了.
Mike: You should have seen that look on Mom's face when I caught her in
我太喜欢那副表情了!那种被挫败之后无地自容的表情.
that lie.I love that look!It's that look of defeat.
杰森:好了,迈克.你妈妈和我正在商量这件事情……
Jason: Right Mike, your Mom and I have been discussing the situation...
迈克:我能猜到.
Mike: I'll bet.
杰森:我们俩都同意,
Jason: And we both agree that it's not fair for you to be grounded while
把你关起来而允许她这周末到亚特兰大对你而言很不公平.
she spends the weekend in Atlantic City.
迈克:嗨,我很高兴你们回心转意了!
Mike: Hey, I'm glad to see you guys came around!
杰森:所以呢,你妈妈也要被关起来.
Jason: So, your mother's been grounded too.
开萝尔:对不起,我没听清楚?
Carol: Excuse me?
迈克:你在玩笑,是吧?
Mike: You're kidding, right?
麦琪:不,迈克.我要把自己关起来,因为我对我的上司撒了个谎.
Maggie: No Mike.I'm grounding myself for lying to my boss.
迈克:哇哇哇,等会儿.你自己关自己禁闭?
Mike: Wow wow wow wait a minute.You're grounding yourself?
麦琪:没错.我觉得这是我以身作则的机会,
Maggie: That's right.I saw the chance to nail myself to the wall and I
所以我没有放过.
took it.
爷爷:你知不知道前门敞着呢?
Grandpa: Did you realize this front door's standing wide open?
本: 举起手来,警官先生!!
Ben: Stick 'em up, copper!!
爷爷:好吧,如果想你就开枪吧.但是,我想给你一个拥抱.
Grandpa: Alright, shoot if you want to.But I'm giving you a hug.
麦琪:爸爸!!!
Maggie: Daddy!!!
奶奶:看见你太高兴了.嗨,小宝贝,你还好么?哦,小迈克!!哦!!
Grandma: Good to see you.Hi sweetheart, how are you?Oh Mikey!!Ohh!!
杰森:非常高兴能见到您……
Jason: And it's good to see you...
爷爷:开萝尔,你还没跟爷爷说声"你好"呢?
Grandpa: Carol, haven't you got a "hello" for your old grandpa?
开萝尔:嗨!!!
Carol: Hey!!!
杰森:凯特!!!(注:开萝尔的学名.)
Jason: Kate!!!
奶奶:哦,杰森,太好了……麦琪,
Grandma: Oh Jason, it's so good....
真对不起,我们晚到了.埃德想给你们准备一份惊喜.
Maggie, I'm so sorry we're late, Ed had to pick up a little surprise for you.
麦琪:哦,爸爸,什么东西?
Maggie: Oh Daddy, What?
爷爷:我……不要太急.看,
Grandpa: I...now not so fast.
小女孩儿都是怎么管她们的爹地要礼物的?(唱歌)
How do little girls ask for something from their pop?(singing)
麦琪:好漂亮,好漂亮,请放点樱桃在上面!(唱歌)
Maggie: Pretty pretty please with cherry on top!(singing)
开萝尔:我想吐.
Carol: I'm gonna gag.
爷爷:辛那塔的票!(注:Francis Albert Sinatra, 1915-1998,意裔美国男明星 )
Grandpa: Sinatra tickets!
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
爷爷:我知道你不会喜欢那什么精神病大夫们的会议,
Grandpa: Well I knew you had to be dreading that shrink convention,
所以听说辛那塔要在亚特兰大演出的消息,
so when I found out that Sinatra was gonna be playing in Atlantic City,
我就打了个电话.
well I just pulled a few strings.
奶奶:我们知道你有多么的喜欢"旧日里的那双蓝眼睛".
Grandma: We know how much you love "old blue eyes".
麦琪:哦,杰森,辛那塔!!
Maggie: Oh Jason, Sinatra!!
杰森:耶,我一直绞尽脑汁想得到这个.
Jason: Yeah, and I've been knocking myself out trying to get these.
爷爷:我保证你会的.
Grandpa: Yeah, I'm sure you did.
麦琪:哦,爸爸,太谢谢你了.
Maggie: Oh Daddy thank you so much.
迈克:对不起,妈妈,可是,你不是要被关禁闭么?
Mike: Ah excuse me Mother but aren't you grounded?
爷爷:什么什么?迈克?
Grandpa: What was that Mikey?
迈克:是这样的,妈妈刚才在您来之前告诉我说,她这周要把自己关到这儿.
Mike: Well Mom was just saying before you got here, how she was grounding herself for this weekend.
麦琪:麦琪,是这样的么?
Grandma: Maggie?
麦琪:对,我说过.
Maggie: That's right, I did.
爷爷:听起来像是你们这些精神病科医生的又一个怪主意.
Grandpa: Sounds like another one of your screwball shrink deals.
杰森:也非常喜欢看到你,埃德.
Jason: It's good to see you too Ed.
麦琪:爸爸,我们打算把迈克关起来,因为他撒谎骗我们.可是,
Maggie: Dad, we're grounding Mike for lying to us,
就今天早上,他发现我向我的上司撒了谎.所以,我把自己关了起来.
and just this morning he caught me lying to my boss.So, I've grounded myself.
奶奶:你当着孩子们的面儿撒谎?
Grandma: You lied in front of the children?
迈克:对.再看看对本是怎么做的吧.
Mike: Yes she has.And look what it's done to little Ben.
麦琪:我觉得杰森和开萝尔现在晚餐表现这会儿也准备的差不多了.
Maggie: Oh I bet Jason and Carol are probably getting ready for the dinner
show about now.
本:现在8点钟,周围一切正常没有发现可疑情况,
Ben: Eight o' clock and the perimeter is secure Grandpa!
爷爷!迈克今天晚上跑不掉!
Mike's not sneaking out tonight!
爷爷:干得好,本 警官.保持警惕.哦,本这孩子没准儿长大了可以成为一位不错的警察.
Grandpa: Good job, Deputy Ben.Carry on.Oh that Benny's gonna make a great cop.
迈克:如果他能活到那时候的话.
Mike: If he lives that long.
Grandma: Ooh, I got a six letter word, triple word score, "sexual
麦琪:妈妈!?
Maggie: Mom!?
奶奶:我的子儿都出完了,我赢了.
Grandma: My tiles are all gone.I win.
迈克:那是连续的六个,奶奶.
Mike: Well, that's six in a row Grandma.
麦琪:好了,迈克.你该上床睡觉了.
Maggie: Well Mike, it's time for you to go to bed.
迈克:什么?才八点.
Mike: What?It's eight o'clock.
麦琪:对,你要接受惩罚了,你不应该再继续玩了.
Maggie: Well you are being punished, you're not supposed to be having fun.
迈克:我不!我要跟你们一起去玩儿.
Mike: I'm not!I'm hanging out with you guys.
麦琪:迈克!睡觉!
Maggie: Mike!Bed!
迈克:好好好,我这就去.但是,我想让你明白,如果我真的发现了一场大火,我就眼睁睁看着那些人去死.
Mike: Ok ok ok, I'll go.But I just want you to know, that if
I ever do spot a towering inferno, I'm just gonna let those people die
麦琪:妈妈,爸爸,再来点咖啡?
Maggie: Mom, Dad, more coffee?
爷爷:好!
Grandpa: Yeah!
奶奶:不!埃德,你会睡不着觉的的.
Grandma: No!Ed you know how it keeps you awake.
麦琪:今晚是尽情享乐的一晚,不要顾忌那么多.
Maggie: Well tonight's the night to stay awake.
八频道全是"爱情七日",
It's all "love week" on channel eight,
今晚上晚些时候,是电影
and tonight's late night movie is, "Love Story two".
奶奶:麦琪,我还以为你真的把自己给关起来了呢.
Grandma: Maggie, I thought you were grounded too.
麦琪:我肯定会的,我不想太沉溺于此.
Maggie: Well sure but, well I don't want to get carried away.
奶奶:你想干什么就去做,没人管你的.
Grandma: You can do what you want.
麦琪:妈妈!爸爸,你能不能跟说说妈妈.
Maggie: Mom!Dad will you explain to her how silly this is.
爷爷:关禁闭的事我一无所知;还有,你为什么要听你老公那个破主意.提起这个,当初的时候,你就不应该嫁给他.
Grandpa: I don't understand anything about this grounding business; or why you listen to one of you husband's half-baked ideas.And for that matter why you'd even marry him in the first place.
麦琪:谢谢你爸爸.
Maggie: Thanks Dad.
奶奶:如果把你换成我,我就上床睡觉,像大人一样接受自己的惩罚.
Grandma: If I were you, I'd go to bed and take my punishment like an adult.
麦琪:我已经是大人了!
Maggie: I am an adult!
奶奶:你现在表现不太像大人啊,你说是不是?
Grandma: Well you're not acting like it now, are you?
爷爷:玛格丽特*凯瑟琳(注:麦琪的全名),你就不要再跟你妈妈争辩了.
Grandpa: Margaret Catherine, don't argue with your mother.
本:八时零五分,一切正常!!
Ben: Eight O five and all is well!!
麦琪:你就是那样想的.
Maggie: That's what you think.
侍者:您看这张桌子可以么,先生?
Waiter: Will this table be satisfactory sir?
杰森:哦,太好了,谢谢.
Jason: Oh this is great, thank you.
侍者:您就要这张桌子,您真的确定么?
Waiter: Are you absolutely certain that this table is to your satisfaction?
杰森:你在开玩笑?什么是好什么是坏,我们分不清楚么,我们差不多紧挨着舞台.
Jason: Are you kidding?What's not to like, we're practically ring side.
侍者:因为我在那边还有一张桌子,非常舒适,在那柱子后面.
Waiter: Because I do have a lovely table back there, behind that pillar.
杰森:那……开萝尔,对于东方赌城你是怎么看的?
Jason: So...Carol, what do you think of the gambling capital of the East?
开萝尔:我觉得那是我去过的地方中最不喜欢的一个.
Carol: I think it's the most disgusting place I've ever been.
杰森:你不开心么?
Jason: Are you not having fun?
开萝尔:你在开玩笑?我太喜欢了!
Carol: Are you kidding?I love it!
侍者2:鸡尾酒?
Waiter 2: Cocktails?
开萝尔:shrimp(脸长得真寒碜).(注:shrimp字面义"虾".英俚语,亦指:身材好但相貌平平甚至丑陋的人.)
Carol: Yeah, shrimp.
侍者2:shrimp(虾米)?
Waiter 2: Shrimp?
杰森:哦,她是说那种小的软壳类动物虾米,不是说你.
Jason: Oh she means the little crustaceans, not you.
侍者:我也觉得她说的不是我.一杯虾米鸡尾酒,那您呢先生?
Waiter: I didn't think she did.One shrimp cocktail, and you sir?
杰森:我来一杯伏特加,就矮的那个……不不,对不起,什么都不加什么都不加.
Jason: Ah, I'll just have a Vodka gimlet on the rocks please, just make it
a short one...no..not, I'm sorry nothing, nothing, nothing
侍者2:精神病科大夫?
Waiter 2: Psychiatrist?
杰森:是的.
Jason: Yes.
侍者2:还真是,一点儿没错.
Waiter 2: Figures.
杰森:哇!辛那塔,现场演出.
Jason: Wow!Sinatra live.
开萝尔:耶!
Carol: Yeah!
杰森:知道么,最精彩的是,
Jason: You know the greatest thing about it is that any or all of his
他的所有朋友都会出场.我们可以看到迪安*马丁,
friends could show up.We could see Dean Martin or Sammy Davis Junior.
小萨米*戴维斯,可能还会看到乔伊主教.
Maybe even Joey Bishop.
开萝尔:我们不是在做梦吧.
Carol: Dare we dream.
(麦琪蹑手蹑脚下楼来看电视)
(Maggie sneaks downstairs to watch TV)
电视:今晚的"爱情七日"继续为您播出.
TV: Tonight's "Love Week" continues with "Love Story 2", Oliver's story.
昨天晚上当中,
Last night in "Love Story 1" Ali McGrath died of a mysterious disease
阿里在辱骂奥尼尔之后死于一种神秘的疾病.
after calling Ryan O'Neil a series of insulting names.
(迈克蹑手蹑脚下楼来要出去)
(Mike sneaks downstairs to go out)
麦琪:要去哪儿?
Maggie: Going somewhere?
迈克:夜游症,我正在夜游.你不相信么?妈妈,我穿的整整齐齐.
Mike: I was sleepwalking.Can you beat that?Look at this Mom, I'm fully dressed!!
麦琪:迈克*亚伦*希佛!!
Maggie: Michael Aaron Seaver!!
为了逃过对你撒谎的惩罚,
Don't you dare compound your escape from your punishment for lying,
你竟敢明目张胆地骗!!
by using deception!!
迈克:您说的我一个字儿也不明白.
Mike: I didn't understand a word of that.
麦琪:坐下!!迈克,你想干什么?
Maggie: Sit down!!Michael what are you thinking?
告诉你做什么你就做什么,做到这点真的很难么?
Is it really that hard to do as you're told?
就给你一点小小的惩罚,你就不能让别人相信你是么?……每一次……
You had a simple punishment, but can you be trusted?No...every single time...
迈克:嗨!!这是什么?
Mike: Hey!!What's this?
麦琪:没什么.
Maggie: Forget that.
迈克:不,那是克里内克丝面巾纸!!你一直在看.
Mike: No, that's a Kleenex!!You've been watching "Love Story".
麦琪:我没!这是.
Maggie: I have not!It was "Love Story 2"!
迈克:对不起,我想知道,你不是正在关禁闭么?
Mike: Excuse me, but aren't you supposed to be grounded?
麦琪:迈克,我们现在说的是你.
Maggie: Michael, we are discussing you.
迈克:好,我明白了.罚你,你可以蹓,你就没事;换了我,就不行.
Mike: Oh, ok I get it.It's ok for you to skip out on your punishment but it's not ok for me.
麦琪:迈克,如果你觉得借惩罚你这件事会给我施加很大压力的话,
Maggie: Michael, if you think I get some great pleasure from punishing you,
那你就错了.
you're wrong.
迈克:得了,
Mike: Oh come on Mom.
妈妈.
I've seen that little glimmer of excitement in your eye when you catch
我已经看到了,当你逮住我做坏事时你眼中那星兴奋的目光;我已经听到了,
me doing something wrong.
当你叫我全名时候那种愉悦的调门.
I've heard that happy ring in your voice when you call me by my full name.
麦琪:迈克,你根本不明白做父母的是怎么过的.
Maggie: Michael, you don't understand what a parent goes through.
迈克:很明显,你不明白我的意思.
Mike: And you sure don't understand me.
麦琪:是的,我不理解.当你像这个样子做事的时候,我就不理解.
Maggie: No I don't.Not when you act like this.
迈克:因为你不理解,
Mike: And because you're confused,
所以我就得放弃今年一年当中最盛大的聚会!
I have to miss out on the biggest party of the year!
麦琪:上周末的聚会你也说是今年最盛大的聚会
Maggie: I thought you said last weekend's party was the biggest party
of the year.
迈克:什么?什么?从现在开始你要对咱们俩的谈话做个记录.
Mike: What?What?You keep transcripts of our conversations now.
麦琪:迈克,在你16岁的时候,每一次聚会都成了今年最大的聚会!
Maggie: Michael, when you're sixteen, every party is the biggest party of the year!
麦琪:你说说当然很容易.
Mike: That's easy for you to say.
但是,你真正明白长到16岁,
I mean what do you know about being sixteen and having a parent who's
身边有一个一贯正确从来不犯错误的母亲会是什么感觉么?
always right?
麦琪:够了!你碰到你爷爷了么?
Maggie: A lot!Have you met my father?
迈克:好心人.
Mike: Pleasant man.
麦琪:好心人?!你知道么,有一次他把我关起来,什么都不为.
Maggie: Pleasant man?!You know once he grounded me for no reason at all.
迈克:什么都不为?
Mike: No?
麦琪:我所能做的只有在吃晚饭的时候骂"该死的".
Maggie: And all I did was say "damn" at the dinner table.
迈克:你?
Mike: You?
麦琪:你爷爷他其实也骂过人"该死的",但是无济于事,
Maggie: And even though he was known to say that, and a lot worse,
他还是把我给关了禁闭!
he still grounded me!
迈克:当然了,他是大人.
Mike: Well of course, he was an adult.
麦琪:你是想谈谈公平的问题么?
Maggie: I mean you want to talk about unfair?
麦琪:我觉得我一直谈的就是.
Mike: I believe I have been.
Maggie: Grounded.Forget the fact it was Vicky Tamara's sweet sixteen party
它还是一个比萨party呢.她还是我最好的朋友呢.
It was a pizza party.I mean she was my best friend.
我应该怎么做?于是,
I mean what was I supposed to do?
So I climbed out the window and went to that party anyway
迈克:哇.
Mike: Wow.
麦琪:而且,那真的是一个名符其实的……美好的……party.
Maggie: And it was a truly...great...party.
迈克:因为是你偷着去的.
Mike: Because you got away with it.
麦琪:对,而且我……
Maggie: Yeah, and I ...
迈克:我能理解.
Mike: I understand.
麦琪:而且,我开始.过来!
Maggie: And I'm beginning to.Come on!
迈克:到哪儿?
Mike: Where?
麦琪:我想吃比萨了.
Maggie: Out!I'm in the mood for pizza.
迈克:可是,妈妈,我们俩现在在关禁闭呢,还没忘吧.
Mike: But Mom Mom, we're grounded remember.
麦琪:如果你不告诉我我刚才做了什么,我就不会告诉我自己.
Maggie: I won't tell me what I did, if you don't.
迈克:这太怪异了.
Mike: This is deeply weird.
开萝尔:那,演出什么时候开始?
Carol: So when does the show start?
杰森:开萝尔,像弗兰克斯*辛那塔这样的超级明星肯定不会在上菜的时候就上场的.
Jason: Carol, a superstar like Frank Sinatra never performs while they're still serving food
开萝尔:那他不觉得有点饿得慌么?
Carol: Does it make him hungry, or what?
杰森:哦,嘘.时间到了!
Jason: Oh, sshhhh.Show time!
主持:女士们,先生们,亚特兰大市勃鲁克饭店非常荣幸地为您奉献一场别具一格的音乐演唱会……下面有请小弗兰克斯*辛那塔先生!
Announcement: Ladies and Gentlemen,
the Jack Pot room of the Ballbrook Hotel in Atlantic City is proud to
present the unique, one-of-a-kind song stylings of a living legend...Mr.
Frank Sinatra Junior!
杰森:小?
Jason: Junior?
开萝尔:这就是说肯定也不会有什么乔伊主教了.
Carol: I suppose this means no Joey Bishop either.
迈克:哧.
Mike: Sshhh.
麦琪:谢谢你给我买来比萨,迈克.自我16岁以来,这是最好吃的比萨了.
Maggie: Thanks for the pizza Mike.It hasn't tasted this good since I was sixteen.
迈克:也谢谢您,让关禁闭也变得如此妙趣横生.
Mike: Yeah well thanks for making getting grounded, fun.
麦琪:迈克,这可不是关键所在.
Maggie: Michael, that wasn't the point of any of this.
麦琪:您刚才说了一声"母亲"是么?
Mike: Do I detect a sound of mother in your voice?
麦琪:迈克*亚伦*希佛!
Maggie: Michael Aaron Seaver!
迈克:看来我没听错.我知道这样的好时光不会长久的.你又开始教训我了,是么?
Mike: Yes I do.I knew this was too good to last.You're gonna tell yourself on me, aren't you?
麦琪:不.
Maggie: Nope.
迈克:嗨,你真的理解我!
Mike: Hey, you do understand me!
麦琪:是,我想是吧.
Maggie: Yeah, I guess I do.
迈克:不喜欢被关在这儿.
Mike: I don't think I like this.
麦琪:我也不.
Maggie: Me either.
迈克:亲爱的迈克,这周末的禁闭干脆取消了,你看怎么样?
Mike: Hey Mike honey, what do you say we just cancel the grounding for the rest of theweekend?
麦琪:不行,迈克.
Maggie: No Mike.
迈克:你想你也很清楚关在这儿一点儿也不爽.
Mike: I thought you knew rotten is was to be grounded.
麦琪:我清楚.但是我还没忘记,
Maggie: I do, but I also remember that every time it was done to me when
我小时候每罚完一次,都会留给我一些难以磨灭的教训 .
I was a kid, they were lessons I never forgot.
这有益于我成长为一个成熟的,负责的人.
And I think it helped mould me into a mature responsible person.Come here.
过来,过来.
Come on.
本:你输了!!!
Ben: You're busted!!!!
爷爷:你能不能听听这个?某个法国演员,名叫维斯*蒙塔……
Grandpa: Will you listen to this?Some French actor by the name of..er..Y Ves Monta....
奶奶:哦,我爱他!!
Grandma: Oh, I love him!!
爷爷:是么?现在,他正在竞选法国总统呢!(注:影射施瓦辛格竞选加州长)为什么会有人这么蠢,要去选一个演员会当总统呢?
Grandpa: Oh yeah?Well he's running for President of France!Why would anybody be dumb enough to vote for an actor to be President?
奶奶:里根也当过演员.
Grandma: Reagan was an actor.
爷爷:但他不是个好演员.
Grandpa: Well yeah, but not a good one.
杰森:哈哈,嗨!埃德!凯特!
Jason: Ha ha hey hi!Ed!Kate!
爷爷:哟.
Grandpa: Yo.
奶奶:说来听听,你们这些幸运儿.亚特兰大城怎么样?
Grandma: Tell me, you lucky people.How was Atlantic City?
开萝尔:真是太棒了.
Carol: Really vabbit.
奶奶:那太了.
Grandma: Oh, that's wonderful.
爷爷:弗兰克呢?(注:即辛那塔的名.)
Grandpa: How was Frank?
杰森:啊……埃德.他这人看起来有点太年轻了.
Jason: Well...Ed, he looks a lot younger in person.
爷爷:越活越年轻了,啊?
Grandpa: Ringyding ding, ah?
杰森:我们感谢您送票给我们的唯一的方法就是,
Jason: The only way we could thank you for getting those tickets,
让他的把大名签在了我们的菜单上.
was by having himautograph the menu.
奶奶:哦,埃德!!爷爷:哦."埃德,
Grandma: Oh Eddy!! Grandpa: Oh."Ed, I was so sorry that you missed the show.
我很遗憾你没能来看演出.知道你是我的歌迷是我的荣幸.你的哥们儿,
It made my day to find out you were a fan.Your pal, Frank." Oh wow..."
弗兰克."哦,哇……"哥们儿".
pal".You know when a big guy like this has time for a regular Joe like
你知道么,当像他这样的有名气的人物给我这么一个普普通通的陌生人一些时间共处……哦……就好像是把我对世界的信念又给唤回来了.00:22:31,900
me...oh....it kind of brings back my faith in the world.